[Music]
Well, hi everyone. Uh, so as Simon said,
I am Drew. I am the head of AI product
here at Tessle. So today I wanted to
talk about how we think of evals or
maybe more accurately how our process
for evals has evolved over time at
Tesla. Uh going through a few stages
that I think are pretty common in my
experience of developing AI features. Uh
but in particular what I want to get out
of this session is sort of convincing
everybody that
eval doesn't have to slow you down. It
doesn't have to sort of be a thing that
blocks progress or is you like oh I got
to add tests to my code. It's more of a
this is a way that you can actually do
really fast iterative development that
feels much much more like flow state fun
gets the whole team involved uh and
really feels like it speeds things up
rather than slowing things down. So to
hop into things I will talk about the
different stages of evals. So I think in
my experience people tend to go through
four sort of distinct phases as they
learn about what it is like to eval uh
both AI features generally but I think
in particular code ccentric evals
there's a lot of sort of like particular
nuances uh and it almost always starts
with vibe based evals something along
the lines of hey I'm a software
developer I'm a product manager I'm you
know anything in between I'm used to
just like building stuff and testing it
like seeing if it works looking a couple
runs like did it compile, did it go
through, why can't I do that for my AI
based features as well, right? So
they'll write a prompt, they'll maybe
pull a model from hugging face,
something like that, and then they will
run it. They'll have three or four,
maybe 10 if they're feeling ambitious
outputs that they'll look at and they'll
just kind of does it feel right? Does it
look
right? There's a few challenges when you
take this approach, right? It's quick to
get off the ground. It's quick to get
started, but first of all, it's
inconsistent, right? Even yourself
looking at the same output, different
times of day, different you're rushed or
there's like small tweaks, are you
really applying all of the same
heristics the same every time? Uh, but
more importantly, it's really hard to
standardize this kind of an eval across
a team or across time, right?
as you revise the
feature, are you really being diligent
about how you compare the output this
time versus last time? And are your
teammates doing the same thing? Uh, it
can also be pretty unrepresentative,
right? So, if you have five to 10
examples that you're running through,
that's not necessarily going to capture
everything that comes from production
traffic, right? It can be good to catch
like really really lowhanging fruit
about Ben formats or things like that,
but that's not going to give you
everything that you want. And it can
also be really hard to action because
it's not very representative. Right?
When you look at a specific example, say
you asked for some code uh to generate
Fibonacci numbers and you get a
recursive
implementation, the model just do that
for Fibonacci or is it because it favors
recursion over iteration generally and
you don't want it to? It's hard to know
those kind of things like where to
target your fix if you don't have a
broader more representative set where
you can sort of generalize. Uh it's
almost like building a platform versus
sort of building a specific feature. You
want to be able to look across many many
use
cases. So let's say I want to fix some
of these things. I want to add a few
more examples, maybe 20 instead of 10.
Maybe I want to standardize some metrics
and things like that. Well, now it's
getting really slow to review these
things by hand, right? Reading code is
slow just on its own. Now imagine every
time you make a feature change, you have
to read 10 to 20 new implementations
from scratch as you go through. And what
you quickly learn is as you try to solve
these problems, you basically just
created a really bad eval, right? Like
you thought you were saving all of this
time by just saying, I'm just going to
run with it. I'm just going to look at
outputs. And maybe for your first debug
session, like that worked pretty well,
but by the time you're 10 10 iterations
in or three days in, you come back to it
next week, my god, this is so much
slower than if you could have just
automated this, right? This we're
getting back to sort of the classic uh
software development loop where you try
to automate things that are going to
happen over and over again so you can
just crank on them really quickly.
So, inevitably, the next step that
everyone hits after they've done some
vibe coding is they usually flip all the
way to the other side and they say,
"Well, that was so bad. I missed all
these things. Like, there's so much I
wasn't getting from it, so I'm going to
do it right this time." And they read a
bunch of blog posts. They read a bunch
of papers about what like really
rigorous evaluation looks like. And they
become sort of quality obsessed, right?
They want to have really representative
hundreds, thousands of examples. They
want to look at all of them and make
sure every single input is exactly
right. They want to handtune some like
universal metric that will tell them
like is this right or is this
wrong? And as a result, it actually ends
up being even slower than before, right?
Like the problem with manual review is
you have to look at a bunch of examples.
The problem with being uber obsessed
with quality of your evals and making
them perfect is you just never ship
anything because you can never finish
the eval that you're trying to build. Uh
so just a few examples of that is say
you want even a 50 example eval.
Creating 50 code examples and annotating
them with the proper output that's not
it's not quick. That could take several
days to a week if it's a really involved
example. If you want more than 50 it
starts to get really out of control. And
then as you're doing it and you're
trying to annotate what the right answer
should be, you're very quickly going to
learn, there's no objective quality bar.
Even if you have like really clean
examples and you think you know exactly
how it should work, there's going to be
disagreement on the readability of the
code, the commenting style. I mean, just
think about when you put a PR up on your
team, how often do people just agree
with everything you chose? Uh, and then
by the time you do come up with
something that balances everything that
people want, like, oh, well, we need to
have like line length less than this,
but we shouldn't use comments in this
way. You know, you sort of layer them
all up. you're going to end up with
something that's so complicated and so
nuanced that the only sort of metric
that you can run in an automated fashion
is an LLM judge which so we'll talk
about later for codecentric evals is
leaving just a lot of value on the table
in terms of what you can do when
evaluating code-based
solutions. So you you sort of jump to
this because you think ah this is the
solution. This is the antithesis to what
came before. But actually it has its own
challenges. And so really the place
you'll end up after you sort of gone
through a few of these revisions is that
eval are a numbers game, right? You have
to sort of let go of the idea that you
can be perfectly in control or that you
can be perfectly out of control and just
look at things and you have to start
taking on a few more nuanced
assumptions. Right? Your inputs, they
don't have to be perfect. They just have
to be representative. It's okay if only
80 to 90, maybe even 70% of them are
like really good if you read them. There
can be some sort of croft in there. Um,
your metrics, they don't have to be
perfect. They can be gameable. They just
need to be directionally correct. Like
your metrics need to tell you things
that are wrong or right about what was
generated. And finally, like really, you
just need to know what do you work on
next? Like what is the lowest hanging
fruit? Where should you be optimizing,
right? And these seem like concessions,
but if you can sort of get into this
mode of like, it just needs to hill
climb me. It just needs to move me up,
you can sort of embrace this zen state
of mind where it's like, ah, I just need
signal. As long as I get signal, we're
going to keep moving in the right
direction. So, this is getting closer to
what we need, right? You can imagine how
once you embrace this mindset, it
becomes easier to start pulling in
synthetic data because, you know, the
data is not perfect, right? The LLM
might cheat on some things or it might
have slightly weird coding standards,
but as long as it's mostly right, that's
good enough. And now you can get data in
a few hours instead of, you know, weeks
of laborious uh manual annotation. Your
diagnostic metrics become much easier to
design, right? They're just these
tightly scoped little things that tell
you something has changed or this is an
outlier relative to other things. And
I'll get into more of like what kind of
metrics you might design in a minute,
but it it frees you up to sort of be a
little more iterative with that. And
then you also sort of turn away from is
this good? And instead you start looking
at is this bad? Like can I detect
moments like oh if it generated a 400
line file for a palendrome detector
that's probably bad, right? like it's
hard to detect if it's the best
palendrome detector, but I can tell that
400 lines with 15 helper functions is
probably not a good
implementation. But you go this route
and you start fragmenting all of your
metrics. You start putting things into
just like hyperfocused things. You've
got some errors in your input. Suddenly,
you've got this massive behemoth of like
a dashboard like how do I make sense of
all this? How do I actually make forward
progress? The whole point was just to
give me signal and move. What happens
when I'm getting too much signal? So,
the answer to that might be like, oh,
just look at some of the examples and
oh, we're back to vibe based eval.
That's not what we want. But what what
do we want? Like, how do we make sense
of all of these new like fragmented
product metrics that we've sort of or uh
quality metrics that we put together?
So the answer is something that at Tesla
is sort of the current state of our
journey. Maybe there's a fifth stage
that we haven't reached yet. Uh but
we've led on what we call productled
evals. And so these really focus upfront
on how do we define good? How do we
define good enough? And how do we
actually know like what is the most
important thing to fix right now? And
you can think of this as a layer on top
of the stage I mentioned before. So
you've created this sort of atomized
view of all of these fine grained
metrics and synthetic data sets that are
sort of statistically good. How do you
harness that and allow it to sort of
move you forward quickly and in a way
that brings the whole team
together? So the first part of this and
the first thing that productled sort of
eval can do is they help you look at the
right data. Now I mentioned that we
don't just want to go back to vibe based
eval where you're looking at a few
examples and you know just spot checking
seeing how it works. Instead what we
want to do is we want to first define
the input distribution. And what we mean
by input distribution is that you want
to work with your product managers, your
CEO, your leads or just you know anyone
on the team to say who are the users
that we are trying to support and what
kinds of content should the feature
handle well. And the goal here is
actually to be really specific. So let's
say you're building an autocomplete
feature or you're building a testr
runner, right? Ideally you would say
what language are we using? Are we doing
unit tests? Are we doing uh integration
tests? But you go even further. Say
things like we're only testing
libraries. Uh for this version, here are
15 examples of the kinds of functions
that we want to be able to write tests
for. Like you really want to push
everyone on the team to really
understand what is the kind of feature
we are building towards. And then on top
of that, you want to define what we call
operation taxonomy. And so this is in a
sense you have a set of functions that
you want to be able to test. What kinds
of tests should you be able to generate,
right? Can you do mocking? Can you do
fixtures for filebased? You you want to
get really specific here, right? Like
there is a temptation to say, oh well,
it's Gen AI. It can do almost anything
altogether. But you want to be able to
push in and say, "Yes, maybe one step
could have many operations it takes out,
but let's carve it up. Let's categorize
what we think are the kinds of tests or
the kinds of operations that we will
generate." Because then what you want to
start doing is creating specific input
examples paired with this gen this
output or this operation is what we
expect. so that you can then say, "Hey,
I want to look at only the things that
we think we need to be good at and
taking the actions that we think we need
to take." And in a minute when I get to
sort of like the metrics that you will
use to surface outliers, you can start
to ask things like I just want to know
which of these operations are we worst
at or is there a certain input that
we're particularly bad at? So that I can
ask the question of like, do we care?
Was that a P 0 input or was that a P1
input? maybe we care about Python more
than JavaScript and so if Python tests
are bad we definitely have to jump into
that but if JavaScript is not that bad I
don't have to worry about it right so it
gives you a little bit of sort of think
of it as like an overlay on top of your
data to say what's important to look at
where do I want to sort of dive in and
spend my manual cycles uh to understand
the quality of the output and the final
piece to this is that once you've got a
sense of your input distribution your
operation
taxonomy you want to generate some
example outputs and you want everyone on
the team to do this because it ends up
being really important product
discovery, right? Like you start looking
at these features and you quickly
realize all of the little edge cases,
nooks and crannies, things that you
didn't think about when you were just
describing this kind of user and we're
going to do this kind of a unit test.
You're like, "Oh, right. like what
happens when I need to mock a thing that
has API keys or what happens when I want
to generate a file but like the format
is like really cumbersome to specify for
the AI like it makes that mistake a lot
right you can get into these kinds of
details and so we really recommend that
everyone on the team runs through a few
like be the LLM of the product for a
second and just generate stuff and
realize what's hard what's easy about
it so once you have a sense of like what
are the areas that you want to look at
like what are the things that you care
about for this version of the feature
and you can expand that over time with
later versions. Uh the next thing you
need to do is figure out what's the
quality bar that we're aiming for. And
we think about this in a very particular
way. I'll get into a minute why we think
about it in a very particular way, but
uh we don't just mean, you know, oh, it
should be good or oh, we just shouldn't
make any mistakes or it should be a
delightful experience for the user. Uh
we want to specify a few specific
things. So the first is going into it,
we want to agree on what the level of
rigor is going to be for this feature.
If we think it's a quick experimental
prototype, we're going to show it to
three or four users or maybe we're even
just going to demo it. We can maybe get
away with n equals 10 for our eval set
size, right? We just kind of need to
know that it roughly is sensible.
But if you want to ship something to
prod and it's going to be business
critical, it's like your core
differentiation, maybe you need an eval
set of a thousand, 2,000 or 100. Agree
on that upfront because one of the most
painful experiences we've had at Tesla
is when we don't align on that upfront.
We get to a point where we're ready to
ship and the team thinks, ah, we have
like we're ready to go. It looks good.
And then they get hit by, oh, but I
don't trust this eval like I don't think
this is good enough. and I saw one or
two examples that weren't good. And so I
want to know why those aren't being
fixed. So you need to get an agreement
on we think this eval set is the right
size, covers the right con like concepts
and inputs. Uh and it's totally fine for
to be anywhere from five to a thousand.
You just need to agree on it. Once you
have that, you want to just do a little
bit of digging. You want to start
looking through outputs. You know,
ideally you have a set of like the input
distribution and the operation taxonomy.
You can use that to do some synthetic
generation. You create some sort of uh
example output for you to look at.
You've manually annotated some of them.
Go through more. Anytime you see
something that looks bad, just think
through like how could I have detected
this? It doesn't need to be one to one,
but it could be like oh this bad one is
really long. It's longer than others. So
maybe I could have a quick metric that's
just what is the length of the
generation or oh this one's really bad
because all of the variables are three
letters or less right so I'll look for
that or oh it doesn't compile that one's
obvious right you start to collect these
like quick iterative metrics that can
sort of just find
outliers and over time you'll start to
get a feel for certain thresholds like
oh if if the function is a 100 lines or
longer it probably was a bad generation
so we're going to set that as one of our
metrics that we target for for
quality. Also in going through this
you've hopefully identified P 0 use
cases. So this is the other thing that
we try to get agreement on. What are the
things uh and this should be defined in
terms of the input distribution so users
and content and operation taxonomy. What
are the things that just can't be wrong?
And when I say can't be wrong, I don't
mean globally because you'll never know.
It's a probabilistic system. But what
are the kind of things where we can't
have any known instances like if we see
this kind of input and this kind of
operation leading to a bad output it
needs to be added to the e eval set and
fixed like we can't launch with any
known instance of this. So you want to
have those specified. And then finally,
once you have all this, once you know
how big your eval set should be, once
you know what your PZ use cases are,
once you've identified some of those
targets around like length of functions,
number of uh methods, anything like
that, then you can sit down and say,
okay, for launch, we think we want
roughly this percentage of packages that
we generate to be below this number of
files or all of these P 0 use cases,
they must be resolved, right? And this
is where you really want to agree that
the eval set and the metrics when they
combine together will give you
confidence to launch. And if you can't
get there, your eval set is not done.
Like you need to be adding more
examples, increasing the rigor, adding
more metrics until everybody can look at
it and say, I agree with
this. So I had a moment here where I was
going to talk about what do you do when
a model is not actually good enough yet?
Like what do you do when your CEO says,
"Oh, 90% quality, 95% quality." And then
you start working and you realize like,
"Oh crap, I think we can only get like
60% quality." Uh, and here at Tesla, we
call that like the the first mover
disadvantage. Like what happens when
you're hitting limitations of the model
before other people and before it's
become sort of a well-known issue that
you can have faith the model providers
themselves are starting to optimize
against or you your team has started to
acrue data where you can actually
fine-tune and improve uh over the base
capabilities and ironically I hit like
this bad generation of an image and said
all right I'll just try again it was a
little better but it was still still not
right tried it
again I I don't think the image
generator can actually generate this,
right? Like I So what do I do now? Do I
start writing some like image like edge
detectors to find text and maybe try to
like fix it to change the version like
change the the lettering or remove blur?
H that's starting to get really
expensive. And what happens when you
know Dolly 7 or Midjourney 12 comes out
and we don't need it anymore. We have
all this crust we've accumulated in our
system, this tech debt. And so what
we've sort of decided with this is that
you at some point are going to reach a
limit with quality where you've done all
the obvious stuff, right? Like you've
tuned prompts. If you if your team is
capable of fine-tuning, you've done some
fine-tuning against it to see what you
can sort of get out of the
model. Anything else is going to be more
than a quick iteration cycle. And at
this point, what we've sort of settled
on is that this is where you need to
flip it around and start designing to
your eval results, right? You now have a
sense of what are your error cases? What
are you good at? What are you bad at?
Don't be afraid to build around that,
right? Like sometimes you can be tempted
to say, I want to just design the
absolute best user experience as though
everything was magic. But that can
really trap you to a point where you've
designed something that you can't launch
because the model's never going to be
ready for it. And so when we say
designing around eval results, the first
is that we focus on the error cases and
we try to think about how can we make
these specific error cases easy to
detect and recover from and then maybe
you get some partial value from them.
We've also thought about how can we give
users options related to these. So like
can we show you multiple implementations
and then tell you like this one passes
these tests, this one passes those
tests, right? And then let the user
reason about it. It's much easier to get
high quality out of multiple iterations
than it is to get it out of just one go
at the uh at the the task. We also avoid
chaining. So if we know a certain step
in the pipeline is bad, we don't then
try to automatically run onto future
steps, right? We say we're going to have
to pause here. We're going to have to
get the user to correct so that we can
move with known good outputs into the
next area. And then finally, we design
for a good data flywheel. So it may not
be good now, but if we can launch
something that gets feedback and gets
data, we can ship the good version with
the better UX to users faster if we can
get a UI that will give us the data that
we need. I think there's a really
important concept here because
oftentimes when you start going down
this route, a concern that will come up
is but that's bad UX, right? Like why
are we putting our problems on the user?
And I think historically that's been a
very very good instinct amongst sort of
the product and design team as we're
sort of working through this. But in the
world of AI is sort of is your job to
figure out how to design a good
experience that also gets you good data.
And essentially that's one of the
durably hard things about AI
development. And so you kind of have to
start thinking about is the fact that
asking for data is a hard thing to do
well isn't an excuse anymore. You have
to figure out a way to get that feedback
because that's going to let you launch
faster and ship more value to your users
over
time. All right, so last step we need to
talk about you've designed your product
around your edge cases, you have an eval
uh you've decided it's ready to launch.
You want to go out and you want to start
iterating. And everybody who's worked on
a product before will know the classic
things you get from here are bug
reports. You have production data that
you can look at. people will start
asking for
features. We shouldn't think about those
anymore. Everything is just booed for
the eval set, right? When a bug report
comes in, we should have a really smooth
flow to get that added directly to the
eval set so the team can keep hill
climbing against it. When we have
production data flowing in, how do we
get synthetic data pipelines running on
that automatically so that we're
refreshing, we're expanding the size of
our eval set automatically?
when a new feature request comes in, we
need to update our input distribution
and our operation taxonomy. And then we
need to make sure that our eval set has
representative examples of that so that
we we need to see are there metrics that
we're missing. Everything goes into that
eval set because the eval set
essentially becomes the Figma mock for
the AI feature. If it's in the eval set,
we know exactly how we're working
against it and we know we're hill
climbing against it to get to better
quality in the next version.
All right. So, there's been a lot of
highlevel principles, you know, how we
think about evals, what we think are the
right things to focus on or the uh ways
to frame the problem. I wanted to leave
a few specific tips uh on two areas in
particular. So, I mentioned that getting
to this more
relaxed we just need signal. It doesn't
need to be perfect. One of the things
that that unlocks is synthetic data. And
so, how do you get good synthetic data?
My number one recommendation is read
papers. You don't need to understand all
of the sort of indepth training
techniques or evaluation criteria or
anything like that. Most papers will
have a section on how they created their
data set. And increasingly today, those
data set sections are gold. They have
all of these methodologies, all these
interesting ideas for how you can do
clever little twists on a problem to get
good synthetic data. Just as two
examples, Wizard LM and Math Shepard are
both papers that have synthetic data
generation techniques in them that we we
don't use the actual things that were
built in those papers, but we use those
data set generation techniques all the
time here at Tessle to create good eval
sets, training sets, anything like that.
Second big thing I want to focus on is
as you start developing synthetic data
pipelines which is becoming one of the
sort of core durably hard things of
modern AI development your filter is
everything right you can generate data
any number of ways if you have a good
filter that reliably strips out noise
you can get to a good data set and so
this is an area it's really worth
investing in using every tool in your
toolbox. Don't be afraid even if it's
like a hard long project to in like
incorporate static analysis into some
sort of like does it compile does this
API match the imports all of that if it
gives you incremental gain in the
quality of your filter can be worth it
uh and in fact usually is is worth it
because it really compounds from your
filter. Uh and the last one is don't be
afraid to overclock your generation,
right? Use the biggest model you can. Uh
it doesn't have to be what you run in
production. You can run like a thousand
branches and then just pick the best
one. Like really go overboard here
because it's all about getting data
quickly. Especially for evals where you
only need a hundred, a thousand, maybe a
couple thousand examples. It's okay if
it's not economically feasible to run it
at
scale. All right, last area. I talked a
lot about metrics, a lot about this idea
that your metrics don't need to be
perfect. They just need to be
directionally correct. They need to give
you good signal. So, the first piece of
advice I have here is keep things small
and like pretty dumb at this case,
right? like lines of code is a great
metric. The overall length of lines,
great metric. How many functions are
there? Do the tests pass? Like things
that are very, very concrete. And then
what you're looking for is not so much
the absolute number, but relative
shifts. You want to know, oh, usually
our lines of code is 100. We made a
change to our prompts and suddenly lines
of code on average is like 300. Like
that's something's wrong. We broke
something. And then what you can do is
you can use these metrics to sort say
show me the longest files, show me the
longest functions. So I can see ah okay
I see what's happening like it
misinterpreted this or it's adding all
these extra comments that we don't need.
So you really just want things that sort
of help you to sort and jump in on the
right area and to help you detect that
something has changed in your base
implementation.
The next one I'll say is that tests are
the absolute gold standard for
evaluating code centric things. Uh we
have basically a built-in oracle that
tells us does is this generation good
and it's does its tests pass. Now a lot
of code doesn't have tests. So this is
again I've mentioned a few areas that
are sort of like durably hard in the new
landscape for code centric AI features.
start developing your capabilities
around writing tests for code. Right? If
you get code from the wild, if you've
generated code, you should have
auxiliary pipelines that can write tests
and good tests for those so you can now
evaluate the quality of them going
forward. This is just like an area that
it pays to be really good
at. I also mentioned that you want to
look for outliers. You want to know not
is this good or is this bad, but just
like is this really different from the
rest of what we're generating? like is
this distribution if it's all centered
here and I've got one all the way over
here why I want to dig in. Right? It
might be okay. It might just be a normal
thing but it can help sort of prioritize
where you spend your manual cycles. Uh
and then finally when you want to ask
that question at the end of the day of
like is this good? Is this bad? Just
understand that that's there's not going
to be like one metric that you define
upfront at the beginning of the project
that's just definitely right. It's going
to look like an amalgamation of many
things, right? You might say that like a
good generation will have less than 200
lines of code. The average line length
will be about 30 characters. Function
count will be roughly equivalent. You
know, there'll be like a ratio of 3:1
private to public in the API or
something like that, right? That isn't
guaranteed, right? You can obviously
immediately think of instances where
that's not a good function or not a good
generation. It's a statistical game. You
say if I set this barrier, then more
often than not, the things that get
flagged, they are good. And the things
that get anti- flagged or sort of like
flagged in the other bucket, they are
bad. And it's statistically right enough
that it gives me the signal I need to
keep moving. So, that was kind of a
whirlwind tour. Covered a lot of the
things we think of here at Tessle. I'm
sure there'll be questions where they
want to dig into certain areas. So, I
will stop there and I will move us over
to questions.
And I think Simon's gonna come up and
join me to offer some. I am. And it's
it's very disappointing to see how the
uh how the cameras slightly moved up
that I know. I'm so sorry about that. I
blame myself. I'm going to have to I'm
going have to deal with that. But yeah,
that's that's a mess issue, not not a
you issue. So So a couple of couple of
interesting uh interesting questions
that we've had. Um actually one one as a
comment actually which I'd love to kind
of like dig into a little bit. Michael
Wolf says, um, I love that you suggest
folks work a number of examples by hand.
There's a lot to learn by digging into
the real problem instead of staying
above it. And I feel like this is
sometimes we sometimes jump to
particularly with I guess something like
eval where it's like a lot of a lot of
tests that you have to run. It's it's a
lot of stuff we need to we need to get
in and amongst that. um is the I guess I
guess in terms of
um let's talk talk through the value of
that in terms of what happens if you
don't do that kind of thing. Yeah. Uh
well so I actually have a few concrete
pieces to this. So first it's a great
point. I think people on your AI team
need to look at data and they need to
you need to hire for it. And so we have
explicit in our interview pipelines, we
look for people who have that sort of
grit, that sort of ability to sit down
and just like look at a bunch of output
and say like, "Oh, this was weird. I dug
in and then I, you know, I spent 30
minutes trying to understand why and
tweaking with it." Like that is just a
thing you have to do. And you have to
understand that your eval sets are going
to take a day, two days, sometimes
longer to put together. And that's like
that is real meaningful work that you
want to do. and the value that you get
out of that in addition to building good
eval sets that obviously can help you
sort of iterate faster. I think of it
like having a good test suite, how much
faster you can develop and push code if
you've got good test coverage. The
bigger one though, and I think the
reason why we really advocate people do
things by hand is the product learnings.
the fact that there are so many edge
cases and things that it's easy to
describe abstractly, but if you don't
understand the task well enough and
where it can go wrong, it's going to be
hard to prompt. It's going to be hard to
design the UI around it. And so, it's
really it's kind of like a new form of
uh user interviews. It's just like data
interviews, you could call it. No,
absolutely. Another question. This is a
this is a fun one. So this one is when
we think about what good looks like, if
there is something which is completely
novel that we're trying to run evals
against, how the heck do we think, oh
yeah, this is a good eval, this is a bad
eval. Um we had um Dez trainer from
inter one of co-founders of intercom on
the podcast from the early days and we
did and and he runs these things that he
calls torture tests and things like
that. And one of the hardest things that
that he kind of like said was the was
the biggest problem is what does good
look like? Yeah. How do we recognize
without needing to lean it into
production straight away to identify
what good looks like what that value is?
So so what do we do with things that are
novel? Yeah. So I have two two ways that
at least we here at Tesla think about
this. First actually going a little bit
against what you were saying is that uh
why not get it in production as soon as
you can, right? And so in particular, if
you know that you're working in a very
novel space where it is really hard to
know what's good enough, it might be
worth thinking about how can we design
our product so that it's easy to ship
things that don't necessarily have good
quality yet, right? So that could be
around designing around optionality,
designing even just like a labeling
system to let people know this feature
is in alpha. But you know, obviously
it's good to go further than that if you
can. But if you know evaluation is going
to be hard and that the end of the day,
you really just want production users to
tell you, this gets back to what I was
saying about we need to get good at
designing interfaces that are good
experiences and give us good data. We
also need to get good at designing
interfaces that are good and don't
necessarily have to be perfect, you
know, AGI to to to work. So that's one
thought is maybe just a push of like can
you launch sooner and can you design to
allow yourself to launch sooner. Yeah.
The other thing I'll say is like there
is always a world for human judgment, LM
as judge. There's these more subjective
measures that again you just want to
find the biggest lowhanging like
oftentimes in my experience launching
launching AI features. People know
they're going to make mistakes. Yeah,
that's not a huge problem. The problem
is when you make stupid mistakes like
things that are just like how could you
possibly have thought this was ready to
ship at this moment and catching that
like you may not be able to tell like is
this really good but you can tell like
is this stupid like is this going to be
embarrassing to us and so again just to
that first mover disadvantage really
focus on that and then getting out there
and then you can start fine-tuning you
it's much easier to solve these problems
when you have training data and eval
data than it is when you're trying to
just do it all sort of conceptually in
the lab. So, just really focus in my
mind on like blunders first and then
that's like really the minimum bar for
launch and then just find a way to
launch from there. Yeah. Awesome. Um,
one uh I just real
uh one one last uh question here or one
one other question here. Um we talked
about iterating in the loop um with
humans. What is the good number when
iterating? Because I presume you can
have too many too few. What's the
Goldilocks number? It's it'll this is an
obnoxious answer, but it'll always vary
a little bit by the problem and by your
team. I would say one easy answer is
everyone on the team should have spent
some time human in the loop like
reviewing examples, coming up with
outputs because you want everybody to
have that sense for how does the feature
work? What are the examples? Beyond
that, I'll say usually one is not a good
idea. So one of the principles behind
the reason why synthetic data is good is
because somewhere along the lines people
realize like oh synthetic data is only
70% accurate but if you run two humans
through a process their agreement is
like 70%. And so it's like synthetic is
about as accurate as a human. So in that
sense if a human's only 70% accurate you
get much better if you can have two
three people running and you can compare
their outputs to one another. It's
called like uh interan annotator
agreement is like a common thing here.
So if you're running humans in the loop
and it's not your core team who you can
just expect to spend 30 minutes on one
example if they need to to get it right
I would say you want at least two
ideally three so you can compare and
break ties and then ideally you want to
be curating that set. So if someone is
consistently off from the other
annotators you're going to want to look
at rotating them out bringing someone
else in. There's like a whole thing here
of designing human annotation loops that
go much deeper, but just to to give some
kind of an actionable number, three. I
would say three. 30 is an okay number if
you're looking if you're not doing like
an annotation job that's so big and so
expensive that you need to really do it
well. In which case, I say go read some
articles online. But, uh, if it's just
like, yeah, I want to know I want like
100 200 examples. I want to send it to
Mechanical Turk or Scale AI or
something, three is a good starting
point. Awesome. And just to just to wrap
up um Michael kind of I mentioned this
is a nice sentiment in the fact that in
a world full of automation we do forget
that learnings happen and we got to
remember it's we need to train as well
right and we need to understand that the
way to train properly is that is that
manual work. So uh yeah follows up user
interviews is better than data use but
it's hard to scale those user
interviews. It seems about that balance
once we Yeah. And it's all about just
layering on tools, right? Like in my
experience, none of the techniques we've
been adding for AI development here have
undercut anything else, right? Like we
still have data sets with lineage. We
still have uh SG boosts used in some
places, right? Like there it's
everything is just like the next level
up. It usually doesn't replace the layer
below it. The same thing with product
development technically. We still talk
to users. You have to we still use our
own intuition. You have to, but now you
can also just look at data to get an
example.
Drew, it's been an absolute pleasure.
Thank you for joining us on Native Con.
So, uh, down here. Yeah, there we
go. Well done. Awesome. Thanks very
much. Get us.